

Resume of Chris Rault

A front-end designer, ideas guy and digital nomad from South Africa Hoekwil, ZA (UTC+2) · chris@smokeyfro.com · linkedin.com/in/chrisrault

Statement

I am a designer and front-end developer with two decades of experience creating websites, themes and a number of plugins. I've worked extensively with WordPress over the past seven years and in that time co-founded multiple theme and plugin brands, helped develop the Morph and Beans theme frameworks, managed a small remote team and worked with clients of all sizes. My current interests include the JAMstack, Vue.js, Gridsome and headless commerce. I am available for remote positions that align with the UTC+2 timezone.

Experience

Freelancing @ SmokeyFro Jun 2019 - Present

- Working on Mzango.com and other side projects.
- Consolodated some of my side projects under the SmokeyFro brand.
- JAMstack site built using Vue.js/Gridsome and multiple data sources.

Developer @ WineFolly Dec 2017 - Jun 2019

- Redesigned and re-built the site from the ground using Googles Accelerated Mobile Pages (AMP) project on both deskop and mobile.
- Implemented an searchable index of 260+ grape and wine landing pages.
- Developed a shortcode builder post type and a suite of Gutenberg blocks.
- Setup a compehensive style guide for the sites components.
- Did ongoing performance optimisation and AB/Testing using Google Optimize.
- Built out a number of custom post types to manage the team, glossary, etc.
- Created landing pages for different marketing initiatives.

Creative Director @ Web Monkeys Jan 2005 - Dec 2017

- Oversaw the creative direction of our various product related brands.
- Implemented 30+ Joomla templates, built up a customer base of 30k.
- Co-founded the Morph template framework and admin interface.
- Managed a small team of developers and support staff all working remotely.
 Co-founded HeadwayRocket with a number of plugins extending the Headway Visual Editor which turned over \$250k revenue in 5 years.
- Co-founded ThemeButler, a theme and plugin club aimed at WordPress developers, centered around our in-house open-source framework Beans.

Technical Consultant @ RPC Data Jan 2001 - Jun 2003

- Product lead for Oracles Forms and Reports, 9i Application Server and Portal
- Assisted sales team with technical demos, presentations and product info.
- Helped create in-house POS using Oracles suite of products.
- Was responsible for maintaining the companies site and internal portal.

Education

Advanced Web Design

University of Cape Town Jan 2001 - June 2002

National Senior Certificate

Die Built Highschool, George Jan 1995 - Dec 1999

Skills

- + Web / UI / Theme Design
- + Front-end Development
- + Technical Writing
- + Customer Support
- + Screencasting / Tutorials
- + Wireframing / Prototyping
- + Performance Optimisation

Tools

- + PHP, HTML, CSS
- + Vue.js / jQuery / Vanilla JS
- + Gridsome / Svelte / Nuxt
- + Matamo Analytics / GA
- + Sanity / Cockpit / Ghost / WP
- + Zeit Now + CLI / Netlify
- + Git / Github / Gitlab
- + Lighthouse / Pingdom

References



Madeline Puckette CEO, Folly Inc







John Coonen
CEO, Coffee Group
CMS Expo Organizer



Brandon McDonaldCEO, RPC Data
Former employer

(i) Contact info on request

